( radio ) ... motorway and the ... .
( Don 't go nyuh if you 're heading out of town for the holiday . )
( Take it easy , drivers , and make sure you get back alive . )
( TV ) With no option but to return to Adelaide last Sunday
( without any clue to their children 's whereabouts . )
( Our next report is from Sydney , )
( where householders in the Wisdern suburbs )
( report flocks of white cockatoos )
( attacking their houses . )
( We contacted the Dept. of Agriculture but )
( they could offer no explanation for the phenomenon )
( except that the birds could have been )
( attempting to correct an imbalance in their diet )
( by eating the wooden surrounds )
( and balcony rails of the houses . )
( Little comfort to the residents who )
( can only watch the birds flocking and hope )
( that they don 't attack again . )
( This is the damage they caused at the home of ... )
Hello ?
Hi , Mark .
Did you just ring a minute ago ?
No , no . No reason .
Oh , will you hold on a sec ?
Hello again .
No , no , we won 't be able to .
Peter 's being a real shit .
You know he is when he digs his heels in .
Actually , we 're , uh , not talking at the moment .
You 're still going to Eldon , aren 't you ?
I mean , just ' cause I can 't .
( phone ) Marsh ? Marsh , you there ?
Hey , what 's going on , Mar ?
Sorry , I dropped something .
I didn 't catch what you said .
( phone ) Where 's Peter gonna drag you off to ?
I don 't know .
Some beach up north . Should be really great
with the weather we 're having .
Shit .
If I had a pint , for sure .
You 're the one that wants to get away early .
Oh well , is everything ready , is it ?
- Nearly . - Huh .
I thought you were gonna ask Mrs. What 's-er-name to feed Cricket .
I didn 't feel right about asking someone we
don 't even know to babysit YOUR dog .
- Well , I 'll ask her . - She 's not home .
I don 't think Cricket 's gonna starve to death
with three whole cans of dog food there .
If ya think she 's fat , she can go without .
She 's too fat anyway .
You can 't just prop a pile a of dog food
down on the porch and expect her to ...
Look , why don 't we take her ?
We 'll take her .
Look at the poor ol ' bugger , y 'know ?
She 's knows we 're going away .
Then why don 't you and Cricket go away
and I 'll stay at home and bark at the birds !
( radio ) Speculations concerning the flying saucer
( UFO as they believe to call it )
( It happened .. that I was so )
( ... during the crisis )
( .. that I learned of the real nature of the Indians . )
I was listening to that .
( radio ) The public ... sleeps ..
( .. unknown to the researcher 's ... )
( It 's calling me ... )
( Which things are defined )
( to decide which ... ? )
What 's that ?
Get in touch with Mark or Frieda ?
Yes .
Told him we couldn 't come ?
Yes !
Can they struggle along without us this weekend ?
- They still going to Eldon ? - Yes !
Aren 't we talking ?
Luv , look , uh ...
I 'm not trying to start anything , I 'm not .
I just think that , uh ...
All things considered , you know , we ...
We .. we should back off for a while , all four of us .
You can lie in the sun . Recuperate .
Recuperate ? !
Anyone would think I 'd been sick !
- Oh no , it 's me too , luv , I need a change . - Oh , my ...
Alright .
Alright , you 're not wild about camping
but you 're not exactly roughing it either .
2000 dollars worth of camping gear
I should hope not ! For that we could have
had a VIP suite at the Southern Cross .
Oh , you 'll be an authority on hotel rooms .
Fucked !
I see .
Jesus .
Bit quiet for a long weekend , isn 't it ?
Too far from the highway to make that much difference .
All we get round here is the lost
and the locals .
Ya in from the Smythe ?
- Yeah . - Oh yeah ?
- Where ya heading ' ? - Moonda . Moonda Beach .
Where 's that ?
It 's just about five miles up the road , isn 't it ?
You heard of any .. Moonda Beach , Kim ?
- No . - Just before the abbatoir ?
Ah , there 's all bloody tracks
and scrub up that way these days .
Ain 't seen much traffic . Not since the sand mining moved out .
Oh ... ' 63 .
'64 , whaddya know ?
Never heard a name Moonda Beach there .
- Where are we ? - Oh , we 're nearly there .
It 's just down the road .
Come on !
Shit !
Hey , Cricket !
G 'day , girl .
You knew , didn 't you ?
That was close .
I ran over a kangaroo tonight .
Well , that looks promising .
Ah , gettin ' close now . I can smell the ocean .
That 's the same tree .
It 's not the same tree . How could it be ?
We 're going round in circles , Peter .
We 've been on the same track for nearly an hour .
- How could it be .. - Then where are we , Peter ?
May I offer a suggestion ?
Let 's go back and spend the night at the hotel .
We 'll sleep in the car .
- Here ? - Yeah .
We must be close now .
We 'll catch some sleep
and we 'll find the beach in the morning .
- I 'm sorry for the ... - Shh !
Stop , Cricket !
Good morning !
Where are we ?
We 're here .
Sun is shining .
- Birds are singing . - Your bacon 's burning .
Shit !
Fuck !
What 'd you do with my clothes ?
What do you want clothes for ?
I mean , who 's gonna see you except me , and a seagull ?
You know , we , uh ..
We just missed the marker last night .
We 'd gone another hundred yards we would 've made it .
Well ..
Don 't congratulate me for doing such an
extraordinary , splendid job of cutting up the camp .
Clever boy .
What have you been doing to the tree ?
- Chopping it down . - Why ?
Why not ?
Hey , come with me . I want to show you something .
Ta-daaa !
What do you reckon , ay ? What do you reckon ?
What do we do for toilets ?
Toilets ? She wants toilets .
I 'm not the outdoors type , Peter .
I love you .
Cross you heart and hope to die ?
- What 's that ? - What ? - There , in your hair !
Bastard !
What did you call me ?
- Nothing ! - Ay ?
Nothing !
Say uncle !
Uncle .
Uncle with sugar on top .
If you don 't get off , I 'll piss myself .
Oh no !
Bully .
Go find a rat !
Go get a rat ! Get a rat !
Go fetch a rat !
Peter !
The tree with the arrow carved in , is it just down the track ?
Yeah , I 'll told ya last night .
If we 'd gone another hundred yards , we woulda been ...
No , a track in theory . How could we have gone around in circles ?
Obviously , we didn 't .
I was right the first time .
Peter !
What 's the matter ? Cricket , shut up !
There 's a thing in the water !
There was a dark shape out there in the water !
It coulda been a shark or something .
What 've you 'd done if I 'd died ?
What kind of question is that , for Chrissake ?
What would you 've done ? Suppose .
Christ ! I don 't know .
Would you 've remarried ?
You didn 't die so let 's forget about it .
Alright ?
What 'd you want for to eat tonight , steak or chicken ?
What 's wrong with a bit of fresh fish ?
Nothing . Except we haven 't got any .
Well , catch some .
I 'll think I 'll defrost something anyway .
Peter , where 's the insecticide ?
In the tent .
What do you think that noise was last night ?
Sounded like a baby crying .
You 're not going to tell me it 's a tomcat . Not out here .
I don 't know , luv .
Not sure I heard anything at all .
Where are you going ?
Oh , I thought I might go for a bit of a wander .
What are you gonna do ?
Think I might ...
Christ !
You all right ?
Jesus Christ !
Funny thing shouldn 't of gone off . It was on safety .
I put the safety on it .
Get the stick ! Go on , fetch the stick !
Fetch the stick ! Fetch the stick !
Drop it .
Come on ! Come on !
All right !
All right , you guys !
This is Clayton , see ?
Shit .
Very funny .
I 'm very cranky .
Sorry .
S ' alright .
- I just can 't get it .. - Don 't worry about it . Y 'know , it 's alright .
Dr. Larkin said it could take a couple of weeks .
Well , it 's , uh , been a couple of months .
Well , I 'm very sorry , Peter . I can 't help it .
Is it .. painful ?
Or is it more of a mental block ?
What exactly is the problem ?
- I 'm only a man who 's gonna have .. - It 's only temporary !
Saw another car down the end of the beach .
Don 't get the place to ourselves .
Look , what 's shitting you anyway ?
- I told you , I 've got a ... - No , I mean what 's REALLY shitting you ?
I 'm bored !
For Chrissakes , bloody false act ,
get off your ass and do something !
Instead of smoking cigarettes and reading dirty books ?
Amuse yourself !
I wanted to go to Eldon , remember ?
Well , alright then , take the car and piss off . Go on , piss off !
Peter , I 'm not the type for crapping in the sunshine
and yawning around campfires .
The water 's too cold , the sun 's too hot .
Alright , then , so what am I supposed to DO ?
Oh , why don 't you go fuck yourself , Marsha ?
Peter !
Peter , it was heading straight for ...
I know , I know .
- It 's all right . - ( babble )
I saw the thing .
But it 's OK , I 'm alright .
I 'm OK now , darling .
It 's OK .
Bit precoccupied , my luv ?
Let 's go home .
We just got here .
Make it worth your while , gorgeous .
How you like where I leave my dirty socks ?
- Should of married your mother . - You 've got better tits .
I 'm serious , Peter .
About marrying my mother ?
About going home .
Why ?
Beat the traffic .
You 're kidding , aren 't ya ?
Yes !
What 'd you do with the chuck ?
I put it back in the fridge .
Luv ?
Marsh ?
- Yeah-ha ? - This chuck 's gone off .
- Couldn 't have . - Well it has .
Fuck , it 's bloody rotten . You musta left it out too long .
- Impossible . - Well , have a look at it .
It couldn 't go off that quick .
It 's got mold on it .
Luv ?
I wasn 't kidding . Let 's get out of here .
- Oh , come on . - I don 't like it .
A little bit of mold ...
I 'm not talking about a fucking chuck !
There 's that thing in the surf .
It 's dead . Anyway , most sharks are harmless .
Peter , it wasn 't a shark .
Of course it was a shark .
Hey , what 's this ?
I think it 's an eagle egg .
Hey , I wonder if you can eat eagle eggs . We can make an omelet .
Gonna crack a beer . D 'ya want one ?
No thanks .
An eagle attacked me !
Jeez !
Eagles don 't attack people .
Spear guns don 't go off with the safety on .
It 's was the chuck .
He was probably after the chuck . You can smell that thing a mile away .
It was a she . She wanted her egg .
But , you didn 't even see it !
Why in the name of God did you do that ?
Just an egg .
It 's a living thing .
What 's the matter with you ?
You KNOW what 's the matter with me !
You didn 't have to smash it !
I didn 't have to have an abortion , Peter !
- What are you doing ? - Leaving !
- Oh , for Chrissakes , Marcia . - No , no that 's it !
I 've had it . You stay and play with the wildlife . I 'll be at the hotel .
Are you coming or not ?
Not !
Hello again .
What 's wrong with it ?
I 've switched it on the alternate battery to run the fridge .
Well , switch it back !
No .
Try the horn .
Marsh ?
Hey !
Hey Marsh ?
Hey Sweetheart ? Sweetheart .
Get out of there .
No possum .
What 's ya doing there , ay ?
Want a nice grape ?
Come on .
Come on . Take the grape .
Marcia ! Marcia , open up for Chrissakes !
Open up !
What 's the matter ?
What 's wrong ?
We 'll leave in the morning .
Oh man !
How 's your head ?
Fine .
Bloody possum .
- I 'll do that . - I don 't mind .
I thought we 'd get an early start .
Let go the guitar !
Don 't scratch it .
Sorry .
Thought we might have time to drive back by the Indian route .
You mean via Hilda ?
No sense in wasting the rest of the weekend .
Well ?
- Can I help you with the tent ? - I 'll do the tent .
Right , I 'll finish packing here .
Spilt the sugar .
I 'm sorry , I 'm only trying to help !
Well , if you want to help , why don 't you go out for a walk
or something and let me do the packing .
I don 't want to go for a walk .
I told you it wasn 't a shark .
No , it certainly isn 't a shark .
Then what is it ?
A " bunya . "
A what ?
It 's a dugong .
A sea cow .
Apparently there used to be thousands of ' em .
All along the coast until the lot were killed off for oil .
Ugly !
It 's not very pretty out of the water , is she ?
Crabs have been at her , by the look of it .
Stinks .
Well ..
There 's the source of the noises you 've been hearing .
She 's probably got a pup in the area .
I reckon the young sound just like a human baby when they cry .
You poor old lady .
... it 'll take ten minutes to get that thing in there ...
Peter , it 's ...
I don 't want to go anywhere .
- I just think it 's a pity to rush off , that 's all . - You promised .
I 'm not saying I want to spend another night here , y 'know .
- You promised . - Look , look .
What 's the difference if we leave this afternoon or ...
You promised !
All right , I 'll drive to the other end of the beach
and see the people camped there , that 's all !
Couple of hours !
We 'll be back here and out of here by 1 or 2 at the latest .
They won 't be there . They 've gone .
What ya think I 'm scared of the dark , Marcia ?
( sings ) If you go down in the woods today ..
you might get a big surprise
If you go down in the woods today ...
you won 't believe your eyes .
Back to being cannibals , are we ?
You wanted to drive up the beach , we 're driving up the beach .
What else do you want ?
It 's not a question of what I want , Marcia .
I mean I realize that I can 't always everything I want .
I accept that .
What you don 't seem able to accept is the fact that the reality of our ..
situation demands ...
You being philosophical ?
There 's no point in talking rationally to you when you 're being philosophical .
I think I see things more clearly than you do , Marcia .
I can stand back and deal with situations in perspective .
I really do see you so much more clearly now .
Self-indulgent maggot .
You drag me to this awful , ugly place ...
You poke your head out of your 2000 dollar shellac
... and call it reality . Take it from me .
You 're not Tarzan and I 'm certainly not Jane by a long shot .
What are you trying to prove ?
Reality , my pet , is ( ) at 5 pm
and dinner parties for the right people and making a whole lot of bread .
Those are your own words , you bastard .
Is reality screwing the neighbors and murdering the unborn ?
You prick !
You were so damned hot for Freda you pushed mark and me together .
And then you bellow like a wounded tomcat when the whole groddy plan backfires in your face .
If it wasn 't murder ..
Why didn 't you tell me right away ?
None of your business .
Do you think I 'd of agreed to having it destroyed ?
Nothing was destroyed !
You said it cried . Those were your words .
Oh stop it ! You pig !
I 'd rather sleep with mad dogs than sleep with you again !
Oh that 's it , yeah , that 's it . Blame me instead of yourself .
- You didn 't want a kid . - Me ? !
Me , I love kids .
Shit , I despise you .
It was all a grotesque mistake , wasn 't it ?
You knew it wasn 't mine .
So you panicked and you attacked .
Just like you attacked that eagle 's egg .
Oh , spare me the grotty symbolism .
Hmph ! This week it 'll be a divorce , next week it 'll be guitar lessons .
You won 't leave me though , sugar .
Because weak as you think I am ..
I 'm all you 've got .
We 'll see .
How we relish the tast of human flesh , ay , luv ?
Neo-cannibals .
Estranged cannibals ... filing for divorce on Monday .
Long weekend , sugar .
You 'll have to miss tennis and do it Tuesday .
- Well , where are they ? - They were here yesterday .
Well , they 're not now .
What are you doing ?
- I 'm gonna have a look around . - Peter .. - I 'll be five minutes , alright ?
Five minutes , I swear to God , I 'll take the car and I 'll leave you here !
( radio ) ... today , conducted its first nuclear test this year ..
( The new China news agency reported the test , )
( the 22nd since China 's first atomic explosion in 1964 , )
( but did not reveal the size of the explosion )
( or say whether it was carried out underground or on the surface . )
( A spokesman said the ... )
( ... at a yield of less than 20 kilotons . )
( ... with Great Britan and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization )
( over British cuts in defense expenditure . )
( The row became public yesterday with the publication of )
( an extraordinarily frank letter from the NATO Secretary General , Dr. Joseph Munz )
Say , fella .
Don 't look at me like that .
See if we can get out of here , ay ?
Marcia !
No !
Let me go !
Can 't we go any faster ?
The last thing we need now is a broken axle .
Well , what took you so long ?
Look , we 're gonna have to notify the authorities .
You notify the authorities ' cause I 'm going straight home !
Where 's Cricket ?
Cricket ?
Cricket !
Was she with us when we went down the beach ?
Don 't know . Haven 't seen her since this morning .
Cricket !
Look down the beach , will ya ? I 'll look around here .
It 's getting late . We 're not gonna make it !
Well , we 'd better hurry then , hadn 't we !
Cricket !
Peter !
It 's still alive , Peter .
Can 't be .
It is !
Come and look at it .
Ah , Jesus ! We can 't just leave without her !
Look , it 's not gonna take very long to go down to the other end of the beach !
- I think I 'm gonna hit you ! - Look , Marcia !
I 'm not leaving without Cricket .
Cricket 's dead .
You 're lying .
I buried her .
Where ?
In the bushes .
You 're lying !
I 'm not going without Cricket .
Be dark soon .
Well , well , well .
Cricket !
Marcia ! Come back !
Wanna come in here ?
Come here with me ?
You wouldn 't leave me , wouldja , girl ?
Ay ?
You wouldn 't leave me ... . wouldja ?
Cricket .
Shut up , Cricket !
Cricket ! Shut up !
Jesus .
Aw , Jesus , Cricket !
Get out of the car , Cricket !
Get out of it !